Guide to the Eric A. Blackall papers, ca. 1939-1989
Blackall, Eric A. papers, ca. 1939-1989
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Eric A. Blackall papers, ca. 1939-1989
14-18-2761
Eric A. (Eric Albert) Blackall, 1914-1989.
8.2 cubic ft.; 2 audiocassettes; 2 reels negative microfilm.
Lecture notes, drafts, typescripts, biographical material, financial papers, correspondence, letters of recommendation, microfilm, audiocassettes, and department files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lecture notes, drafts and typescripts for articles and books, including Goethe and the Novel; also lecture notes and texts for his course "Great Moments in German Literature"; notes from Cambridge University; biographical material, financial papers, correspondence, letters of recommendation, and audiocassettes of Blackall's memorial service of 27 January 1990; and German Literature Department files.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Scholar and critic of German and Austrian literature. Cornell University Professor of German literature.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Lecture notes, drafts and typescripts for articles and books, including Goethe and the Novel; also lecture notes and texts for his course "Great Moments in German Literature"; notes from Cambridge University; biographical material, financial papers, correspondence, letters of recommendation, and audiocassettes of Blackall's memorial service of 27 January 1990; and German Literature Department files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Blackall, Eric A. (Eric Albert); Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832.; Blackall, Eric A. (Eric Albert). Goethe and the novel.; Cornell University. Dept. of German Literature.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
German literature--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted in part.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Class notes
Boxes 1-4
Series II. Manuscript of unpublished German version of Goethe and the Novel; other manuscripts, drafts, and typescripts
Box 5
Series III. Manuscripts, drafts, and typescripts; correspondence, records of the Department of German Literature at Cornell (RESTRICTED in part)
Box 6
Series IV. Correspondence, records of the Department of German Literature at Cornell; biographical material; lectures
Boxes 7-9
Series V. Cambridge University class notes; other miscellaneous papers
Box 10
Series VI. RESTRICTED
Box 11
Series VII. Microfilms and audiotapes
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Class notes
  - Goethe (grad) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Goethe (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faust (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - 355 Goethe (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Goethe as Dramatist (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hamann (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Medieval (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Austria (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baroque (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bibliography (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Büchner (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Wagner (Box 1, Folder 16-21)
  - Seminar: From the Wanderjahre to the Buddenbrooks (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dostoevski (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kant (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Heine (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Lessing (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - German Comedy 1660-1800 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Germany 1850-1890 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
  - Germany 1890-1914 (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
  - Schiller (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Schiller Centenary Lecture (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Schnitzler (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - German History 1792-1914 (Box 1, Folder 37-39)
  - 1954 - 16th Century Germany (Box 1, Folder 40-41)
  - 17th German (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
  - Austria (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - 1954 - The Young Herder (Box 1, Folder 45-46)
  - 1952 - The Gothic Language in its Teutonic Setting (Box 1, Folder 47-48)
  - Lectures I-IX - The Growth of the German Vocabulary (Box 1, Folder 49-50)
  - Lectures X-XVI - The Growth of the German Vocabulary (Box 1, Folder 51-52)
  - History of German Language - Second Year I (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - History of German Language - Second Year II (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - History of German Language - Third Year I (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - History of German Language - Third Year II (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
  - Reader (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Sturm und Drang (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hofmannsthal (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - (material for) The Shadow of Brecht (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Heinrich von Kleist (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Nietzsche (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Keller (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "To be sorted" (Box 2, Folder 18-23)
  - German (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Chapter I Leibnitz and Thomasius (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Chapter II Christian Wolff (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Chapter IV Gottsched and the Stabilization of the ....[?] (Box 2, Folder 27-29)
  - Chapter V Theory of Prose Style; Chapter VI Development of Narrative Prose (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
  - 18th Century Fausts other than Goethe (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - In Progress: Nürnberger (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
  - Nürnberger (copy) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Goethe's Poetry (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
  - 19th Century Fausts (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 20th Century Fausts (Box 2, Folder 39-41)
  - Novel - 18th Century (Box 2, Folder 42-44)
  - Chapter III - the Library Journals (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Romantic Theory of the Novel (Box 2, Folder 46-48)
  - Novel (general) (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Novels (Box 2, Folder 50-52)
  - Arnim - general (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Bonaventura - Nachtwachen (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Brentano - Godwi, Galeerensklave [?] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Brentano - general (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Eichendorff - general (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
  - Fichte (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Hoffman - general (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Hoffman - novels (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Hölderlin - general (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hölderlin - Hyperion (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Immermann (general) (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - The Artistic Texture of Die Epigonen (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Louvet de Couvray (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Novalis - general (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Novalis - Novels and Novel Theory (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - Jean Paul - general (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - Schelling (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - A. W. Schlegel (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Dorothea Schlegel (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - F. Schlegel - Lucinda (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Friedrich Schlegel (Box 3, Folder 28-30)
  - Romantic Science and Lebens.. .[?] (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Tieck - general (Box 3, Folder 32-34)
  - Tieck - novels (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Wackenroder (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Romanticism (Box 3, Folder 37-40)
  - 17th Century Novels - analyses (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Lenau (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Don Juan and Faust (Ms.) (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Don Juan and Faust I (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Don Juan and Faust II (Box 3, Folder 45-47)
  - Goethe and the Novel Part I (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Goethe and the Novel Part II (Box 3, Folder 49-50)
  - Goethe and the Novel Form Chapter II (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Goethe and Mme. de Staël (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Benjamin Constant and Goethe - footnotes (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Chateaubriand (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Goethe and Rousseau (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Goethe and the Novelists Chapter I (Box 3, Folder 56-59)
  - 1964 - The Narrator in Goethe's Werther (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - III Werther - The First (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Chapter V - The Second Werther (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Chapter IV Sendung (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Lehrjahre - Critical Comment (Box 3, Folder 64-67)
  - Wahlverwandtschaften (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - The First Wanderjahre (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - The False Wanderjahre (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Wilhelm Meister's "pious pilgrimage" (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1962 - Unterhaltungen (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dichtung und Wahrheit (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Stella (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Jena Review (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chinese Novel (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lit. 309 Development of European Novel I (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Wezel (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Great Moments Lectures 1-5 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Great Moments Lectures 6-10 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Great Moments Lectures 11-15 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Great Moments Lectures 16-20 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Great Moments Lectures 21-26a (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Great Moments Lectures 27-32 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Great Moments Lectures 33-36 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Great Moments Lectures 37-40 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Great Moments Lectures 42-46a (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Great Moments Lectures 47-50 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Great Moments Lectures 51-57 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Great Moments Lectures 58-60 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Great Moments Lectures 61-70 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Great Moments Lectures 71-76 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Great Moments Lectures 77-82 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Novels of the Romantic Era I (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Novels of the Romantic Era II (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Romantic Novels - Jean Paul Richter (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - 18th Century Novels - analyses (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Goethe - Proserpina (+ Triumph der Empfindsamkeit) (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Proserpina (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 20th Century Fausts (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - 20th Century Fausts (for Indiana) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - 1957 - The Language of Sturm und Drang (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Faust Material - London (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Faust - London text (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Goethe (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Don Juan and Faust (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - The Buch des Unmuts in Goethe's West-Östlicher Divan (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - The Language of Heaven: Reflections of the Bergschluchten" (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Material for Language of Heaven (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Woldemar Nürnberger and His Faust (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Offprints by Blackall (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - The Language of Goethe's Götz von Berlichingen (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - The German Literary Language in 1776 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - "Fernando's Problem" (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - A Planned Volume Essays (Nov. 1987) (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Raabe [?] (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - #2 "The Language of Heaven: Reflections of the Bergschluchten (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - #5 Lotte and Ossian (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - #9 The Language of Egmont (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - #11 "Faust's Temptation in the Wilderness" (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - #12 The Buch des Unmuts in Goethe's West-Östlicher Divan (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - "Faust's Last Speech" (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Series II. Manuscript of unpublished German version of Goethe and the Novel; other manuscripts, drafts, and typescripts
  Note by Jean F. Blackall on Goethe und der Roman: "This is the original ms. and it is longer than the one subsequently published by the Cornell University Press in English. The English Version was written from this ms."
  - 18th Century Novel (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Romantic Novel (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Table of Contents re: projected posthumous Goethe book (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Essay Project (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - Olschner - re: Goethe book (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Reviews of the German Romantic Novel (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - My Faust Essays (towards a book?) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - First copy - unpublished ms. of German Version of Goethe and the Novel (Box 5, Folder 11-27)
  - Goethe and the Novel footnotes (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
  - Second copy of Goethe und der Roman: German ms. of Goethe and the Novel (unpublished) 1-4 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Second copy of Goethe und der Roman: German ms. of Goethe and the Novel (unpublished) 5-8 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Second copy of Goethe und der Roman: German ms. of Goethe and the Novel (unpublished) 9-13 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Second copy of Goethe und der Roman: German ms. of Goethe and the Novel (unpublished) 14-16 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Second copy of Goethe und der Roman: German ms. of Goethe and the Novel (unpublished) 17-20 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Second copy of Goethe und der Roman: German ms. of Goethe and the Novel (unpublished) 21-24 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Footnotes - Chapter 1-13 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - XV Goethe, etc. (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - XV Sturm und Drang (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - The Golden Touch (Box 5, Folder 39-41)
  - The Language of Sturm und Drang - 1957 paper (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - John Paul Schiller lecture (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Series III. Manuscripts, drafts, and typescripts; correspondence, records of the Department of German Literature at Cornell (RESTRICTED in part)
  - Footnotes - Chapter 14-end + (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Style II Emergence - Chapter 11 - The Prose of Maturity (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Style II Chapter 10 - The Grand Manner (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Style II Chapter 9 - The revival of metaphor (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Style II Chapter 8 - The development of the poetical medium (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Style II Chapter 7 - The Language of Poetry (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
  - Style III Emergence - Chapter 12 - Art and Feeling (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
  - Style III Chapter 13 - The Mystical (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Style III Chapter 14 - The Return to Origins (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
  - Arts College Faculty (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Graduate Field - German, 1972-77 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Graduate Exam Questions, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - English Goethe Society (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Goethe in der Roman, 1973-74 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Wilhelm Meister's Apprenticeship Lecture (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Goethe and the Novel, 1976-84 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Goethe and the Novel, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Freshman Seminar, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - London Lecture Materials - Faust, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - London Lectures, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Faust Conference, October 1987 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Emergence (German), 1966-76 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Emergence, 1971-81 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Emergence, 1959-65 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 18th Century Studies (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Departmental Meetings - minutes, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Cornell University Press, 1959-84 (Box 6, Folder 35-36)
  - Hefner and Sons, 1958-78 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Grant and Cuttler Ltd. (International), 1977-78 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Avalon Chair, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1976-88 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - RESTRICTED until 2014 (Box 6, Folder 42-47)
  - Retirement 1984-85 (Box 6, Folder 48-49)
  - Graduate Students, 1968-81 (Box 6, Folder 50-52)
- Series IV. Correspondence, records of the Department of German Literature at Cornell; biographical material; lectures
  Note by Jean F. Blackall: "In the file marked 'Various Lectures' and in folders throughout these boxes there are typescripts of many public lectures given by Eric Blackall. Though many of his lectures were published, I believe that there are others here which have not."
  - Grillparzer Lecture (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Harvard - Visiting Committee, 1979-84 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hull Fund (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Husa - Ode, 1967-68 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Internationale Vereinigung für Germanische Sprachen (IVG), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - London Lectures, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Various Personal (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Metzler, 1968-76 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Metzler - Goethe, 1979-86 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Modern Language Association, 1979-86 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Novels of the Romantics (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Schurman Professorship (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
  - Society for the Humanities (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Suhrkampf - Goethe Edition, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
  - University Faculty, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Vienna Lecture, 1982-84 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Goethe Edition (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Blackall Biographical File (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Memorial Articles (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Memorial Service Program (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Personal (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - General Personal (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Politzer - Correspondence and Lectures (Box 7, Folder 30-34)
  - Aufklärung (Box 7, Folder 35-38)
  - Hegel (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Kleist (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - "To be arranged" (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Droste-Hulshoff (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Goethe (notes) (Box 7, Folder 43-44)
  - Herder (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Schmohl (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Büchner (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Die Mitschuldigen (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Nineteenth Century Drama (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Kafka's Stoker (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Kafka (Box 7, Folder 51-52)
  - Kafka's Vision of America (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Galileo (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Jean Paul (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Philosophical Background (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Junges Deutschland (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Feuchtersleben (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Mörike (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Sealsfield (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Stifter (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Tolstoy (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wieland (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hebbel (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Grillparzer (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - Various Lectures (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Various Notes - E.T.A. Hoffman (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Great Moments Lectures (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Faust and the devils (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Faust questioning Mephistopheles (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Der römische Brunnen (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Strasburg, Frankfurt, Wetzler, Weimar (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Poems by Josef von Eichendorff (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Stefan George (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Romantic theory of poetry (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Great Moments Lectures: The originality of Heinrich von Kleist (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Stifter on the great and the small (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Friedrich Schlegel - Universalpoesie (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Schlegel - Selected fragments (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Rilke's Ninth Duino Elegy (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Brecht and Mutter Courage (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Tieck - Die verkehrte Welt (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Romantic Drama (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Minnesang (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Great Moments Lectures: Hildebrandslied (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - ["---wondrous picture that I can sketch for myself of music ..."] (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Simplicius Simplicissimus (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Walter - stencil 5 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Some Early Poetic Moments - stencil 3 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Tristan and the language of love - stencil 7 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Some passages from Parzival - stencil 8 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Naive and Sentimental Poetry - stencil 15 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - ["Friedrich sagte ..."] (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - German 201 - "Dort hoch auf jenem Berge ..." (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - German 417 - Great Moments (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - A. W. Schlegel - Berlin Lectures (first sections) (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Romantic Materials (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Passage from Wackenroder's Herzensergiessungen (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Nietzsche on the World (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Poems by Mörike (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Goethe - Faust, Act IV Summary (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - The 1587 Faust book (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Lessing - Nathan (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Great Moments - 12A (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Herder and King Lear (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - The great moments in Goethe's Weimar drama (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Goethe on his own Novelle (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Poetry translated for course 39-D (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Selections of German Poetry from the Beginning to 1720 - for German 39-A (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Death and the Plowman (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Selections from Twelve German Poets of the Nineteenth Century for German 39-C (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Der St. Stephansdom in Wien (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Maps (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Peasant Bardolatry: Uli Bräker and his Shakespeare book - paper, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Swiss Peasant - Bräker (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
  - Bräker Materials (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ulrich Bräker und Eschenburg (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1988-89 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lectures for 201-202 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "General - Scholarly" (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Novels of the German Romantics - Lectures to Society for the Humanities (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Harvard Lectures, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Art and Reality - Goethe's Novels (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Lecture, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Sense and Nonsense in Wilhelm Meisters Lehrjahre (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Series V. Cambridge University class notes; other miscellaneous papers
  Note by Jean F. Blackall: "Eric gave a very popular course called `Great Moments in German Literature' - sometimes known as `Eric's Great Moments.' The lectures are among his papers but I do not know whether the selections to which they refer are identified other than by these mimeographs."
  - Great Moments: Heine - Doctor Faust (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Great Moments: Heine's Irony (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Great Moments: Appollonian and Dionysian (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Great Moments: Schedule (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Great Moments: Keller and the "golden superfluity of life" (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Great Moments: Brecht - Episches Theater (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hauptmenn's Die Weber - High German translation (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Nibelungenlied - stencil 6 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Unverhofftes Wiedersehen (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - The fruits of Enlightenment (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Faust - Part II (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Plain speaking and plain thinking (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Hebbel's conception of drama (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Material for History of the German Language (Box 10, Folder 14-21)
  - "Miscellaneous - unsorted" (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hugo von Hofmannsthal: Electra (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Series VI. RESTRICTED
  - Contains folders 42-47 from Box 6, which are restricted until 2014 (Box 11)
- Series VII. Microfilms and audiotapes
  - Microfilm: Nicolaus Vogt, Die Rhein am Rhein
  - Microfilm: Christian August Vulpius, Don Juan den Wüstling ...
  - Audiocassettes of Blackall's memorial service of 27 January 1990, tr6784a, tr6785a